Ayush Sharma

Personal website: https://ayushsharma.dev/

Email: ayushs217@gmail.com Telephone: +1 (678)-330-0438

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern – Northrop Grumman (05/2020 – 08/2020)

- Developed a Microsoft PowerApp for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) Public Health Department which handles automated testing with PowerBI, PowerAutomate and Python.
- Lead a team of 3 interns to design a second PowerApp for the CDC Project Research Center to allow users to add research projects for the Department of Non-Infectious Diseases.
- Improved and updated UI for multiple CDC Administrator Apps.
- Implemented a REST API and used Java Script to automate facts sheets for all 50 US States for the Office on Smoking & Health.

STEM Mentor – Georgia Institute of Technology (09/2019 – Present)

- Employed at CEISMC (Center for Education Integrating Science, Mathematics and Computing) at Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Taught High School sophomore & juniors about STEM at the Davis Charter Senior Academy & Henry W. Grady High School.
- Worked with Horizons and K.I.D.S/STEAM program at Georgia Institute of Technology.
- Teaching elementary and middle school kids about the wonders of STEM.

Chief Executive Officer – 4 Years LLC (05/2018 – Present)

- 4 Years was created in order to help international and domestic students get into top US Universities. All services, such as the ASD, are free of charge.
- Lead developer of 4 Years website and Accepted Student Database.
- Designed and implemented a customer and employee login system of 75 users by provisioning Google Firebase and Cloud Firestore.
- Manages ACT Tutoring team of 20 and website development team of 5.
- Partnered with Microsoft to sponsor a free college exposition panel event on November 27th, 2019.

EDUCATION

Georgia State University Honors College (2019 – 2023)

- Member of the Computer Science Club, Panther Hackers & IEEE.
- In charge of organization logistics to plan GSU Health Hackathon in March 2020. (Switched to virtual format)
- Dean's List (Fall 2020 & Spring 2021)

Alpharetta High School (2015 – 2019)

Graduated with Honors and ended with a 3.94 GPA.

ABOUT ME

Sophmore Undergraduate Computer Science major from Georgia State University (3.86 GPA) with experience in various fields of technology and engineering.

I have had the pleasure to work for technology conglomerates, universities and 501c (3) non-profit organizations such as Lockheed Martin, Microsoft, Georgia Institute of Technology, North American Thrombosis Forum, International Rescue Committee, Pennies for Patients and the Red Cross.

Industrious, diligent and fast learning student with 4+ years of experience in a technology real-world environment.

Soft Skills: Adaptability, Fast-Learner, Problem Solving, Project Management and Leadership

Technical Skills: Python, Java, HTML, JavaScript, SwiftUI, React Native, Firebase, Cloud Firestore and AWS.

Awards: GSU Panther Hacakthon 6th place – Business Intelligence

Personal Projects: 4 Years Mentor System – Fully operational website with an embedded NoSQL Database to live track all mentors logged in hours and payments. Built with Google Firebase, Cloud Firestore, Python, JavaScript and HTML.